<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lifestyle on Mr. Popov</title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/lifestyle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lifestyle on Mr. Popov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniil Popov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:11:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Travel Policy</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-travel-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:11:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-travel-policy/</guid>
      <description>General guidelines
✅ As the best practice we use the most affordable and efficient type of transportation and stays. The price of the stay and travel must be free or the provider has to pay our company for promoting them on tiktok. For those employees who didn’t reach 5 mln. subscribers and not able to get a bargain with the provider, the price of the stay and transportation must be covered by the employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Space Journey</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/mini-space-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:59:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/mini-space-journey/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally released 🎉 Use for social media: #MiniSpaceJourney
&amp;ldquo;Mini Space Journey&amp;rdquo; is an innovative game for the Apple Watch that takes players on a thrilling adventure through outer space. Instead of using the watch&amp;rsquo;s accelerometer and gyroscope, the game utilizes the unique crown button on the side of the watch to navigate the player&amp;rsquo;s spacecraft. This makes for a unique and interactive gaming experience that is not found in other Apple Watch games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Opportunity of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-opportunity-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-opportunity-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>✅ Motivating and adequate leader charging you with motivation for the whole day. You will grow as a professional and become stronger personality. We won’t use shocker on you for first week.
✅ Young team, this year we had just one fight. The oldest developer is 59, but he has a young soul and using electro scooter. Great atmosphere in the office where we blame everyone equally.
✅ Modern technical stack, php 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steamdeck for Whom?</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/steamdeck-for-whom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 11:20:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/steamdeck-for-whom/</guid>
      <description>Look dear readers, I’m not even suppose to write such an articles, since I’m an inspiring manager and have to motivate people becoming better and so on. I not going to lie right, manager in IT department has nothing to do with people motivation or being a great example for productivity. I play games and fuck it, I like it.
I used to fly quite a lot and still do and I was constantly looking for on-the-go solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Became Digital Nomad CTO</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/how-i-became-digital-nomad-cto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/how-i-became-digital-nomad-cto/</guid>
      <description>Or how I moved with one backpack and half suitcase. Foreword This story has begun on 08.06 of 2021. The CEO of our company invited me to his office. We discussed my half year review and etc, and he put an offer in front of me. I went through, and I have to admit it was a nice package. But here is a small thing, I had to move to Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notion Github Backup</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/notion-github-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 17:11:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/notion-github-backup/</guid>
      <description>Data is expensive I write around 2-3 important notes a day. And don&amp;rsquo;t actually worry if my laptop will be stolen, but the data on it..
Since Im heavy notion user I was looking for automated backup solution. Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t trust notion, trust but verify, right?
Backup Create a private github repo Go to actions tab and click on set up a workflow yourself -&amp;gt; Paste this yml file name: &amp;#34;Notion backup&amp;#34; on: push: branches: - main schedule: - cron: &amp;#34;0 0 * * *&amp;#34; jobs: backup: runs-on: ubuntu-latest name: Backup timeout-minutes: 15 steps: - uses: actions/checkout@v2 - uses: actions/setup-node@v2 with: node-version: &amp;#39;12&amp;#39; - name: Setup dependencies run: npm install -g notion-backup - name: Run backup run: notion-backup env: NOTION_TOKEN: ${{ secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive blog post or Github Codespaces</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/recursive-blog-post-codespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 21:19:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/recursive-blog-post-codespaces/</guid>
      <description>I already posted a few thoughts about the iPad in the life of a developer. When I got a message from GitHub that I have beta access to codespaces I was super excited and started looking for a project which I can try to move to the cloud development environment to try it out. Due to the lack of small cozy projects which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t require docker-compose with 10 services, the first thing which I setup here is my blog since it&amp;rsquo;s just Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BasicBB</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/basicbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 19:40:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/basicbb/</guid>
      <description>Basic Building Blocks My blog and GitHub slightly empty in the past few months. I started spending less time on coding itself. I guess this happened to me naturally. I was a software engineer for the past five years and I was building amazing things in good teams and companies. I started to feel that I would like to help other people more than being focus on personal success.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I started spending much more of my spare time on our family project which is called basicbb - Basic Building Blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>https://typ.life</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/typ.life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 13:19:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/typ.life/</guid>
      <description>r/mk Due to quarantine, I had to set up my first home office. I never had anything at home except a laptop, because I can work anywhere, like in the office, cafe, park but not at ducking home. I have no idea how people can concentrate and don&amp;rsquo;t open the fridge every five minutes&amp;hellip; So, I had to suffer&amp;hellip; And I decided to adapt my small cabinet to trick my brain that I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Must Play iOS Games</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/must-play-ios-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/must-play-ios-games/</guid>
      <description>After I started working from home I got a bit more time to play games and would like to share my favorite ones. There are a few criteria by which I was compiling these lists. First of all, games should be optimized for the iPhone and iPad, games shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bugs or unstable performance. And of course, keep in mind that it&amp;rsquo;s my taste and I would love to discover new projects - drop your favorite in comments below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t go to IT or even go out</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/dont-go-to-it-or-even-go-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:58:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/dont-go-to-it-or-even-go-out/</guid>
      <description>During massive panic around the world I got stuck at home the same as a lot of other people probably. And a lot of my friends watching on me because not much changed in my life, I didn’t lose my job and I busy every day even due to massive panic which causes lockdown. So, they started asking me what should I do to become a developer like you and do millions per month?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad - Do You Need It?</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/ipad-do-you-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 10:51:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/ipad-do-you-need-it/</guid>
      <description>I decided to share this thoughts, cause of purchasing new iPad pro. I was thinking for last few years, do I really need an iPad? I used to think that it&amp;rsquo;s completely useless device. If I have MacBook as main working machine and iPhone as secondary/helper. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about this device from programmer/manager perspective.
Zoom, right? MacBook has the shittiest camera on the market, for some of my coworkers it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound as disadvantage, because they simply don&amp;rsquo;t use camera for syncs and meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad HR experience or How new repo was born</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/bad-hr-experience-or-how-new-repo-was-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:03:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/bad-hr-experience-or-how-new-repo-was-born/</guid>
      <description>Logektor ⚡️ Forewords This repo has some background, let me tell about it. Once, quite some time ago, I came to the company on the interview, for quite good and interesting position. We were talking about what they need and what I will need to do on this position. Meeting it self was good and I was so excited about that position.
But after few days I received tests assignment from them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
