<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on </title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 12:56:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improve and Do Retrospectives Right</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/improve-and-do-retrospectives-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 12:56:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/improve-and-do-retrospectives-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Improving daily work is even more important than doing daily work.”
&lt;strong&gt;Gene Kim&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17255186-the-phoenix-project&#34;&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often as managers, we try to be a great example, lead by example and work as hard as we can and this is related to
any leaders, team leads, managers, CEOs and etc.
All of this is nice, but will never lead to great results, as a single person you cannot impact the results of the whole company,
no matter how great, fast, experienced you are. There is always a team and more than one person behind success. I stumbled upon one concept which is called &amp;ldquo;multiplier&amp;rdquo; from the same name book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8310410-multipliers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Multipliers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, that was eye opening for me. Instead of pushing yourself you must educate and mentor others, as you will work as the &amp;ldquo;multiplier&amp;rdquo; and bring much more value towards the company/business/team/department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bit About Scrum and Its History</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/a-bit-about-scrum-and-its-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 13:26:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/a-bit-about-scrum-and-its-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was inspired about SCRUM methodology back in 2018 when for the first time I read a book named &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12426548-the-scrum-field-guide&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The SCRUM Field Guide&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; which written by Mitch Lacey. Back in the day I used to be an engineer and I could not realize all benefits of adapting this methodology and was blindly following what team lead was saying. Nowadays when I&amp;rsquo;m in charge of success of more than 20 people, that&amp;rsquo;s where I had to come back to this book and write down all important notes which I would like to share. As well as to share how and where scrum methodology and agile principles started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
