<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on Mr. Popov</title>
    <link>/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on Mr. Popov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniil Popov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 10:07:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Env in Go V2</title>
      <link>/posts/flexible-env-in-go-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 10:07:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/flexible-env-in-go-v2/</guid>
      <description>lalabuy948/genvutils Motivation As you probably saw my founding of two nice libraries that allow you beauty and easy abstraction on dot and just environment variables. You can check it there
After some time I decided to create another open-source library for the world and I merged the functionality of packages which you can find in the article above. I started from scratch and you are more than welcome to have look on it on my GitHub -&amp;gt; github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashicorp Vault as Environment Manager</title>
      <link>/posts/hashicorp-vault-as-environment-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 20:09:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hashicorp-vault-as-environment-manager/</guid>
      <description>How to use Hashicorp Vault as dot environment manager? I decided to share this because I was looking for small, simple and easy to use tool where I would store dotenv secrets for my apps. And I found this nice and elegant solution which will allow you to control your application secrets with small bash script. 🙂
Pre Requirements  Installed vault Finish setup instructions  You can find nicely described steps here: Getting started</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Scaling - Companies collaboration</title>
      <link>/tech-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech-scaling/</guid>
      <description>TechScaling - Service provided by d.labs to other technology companies in pure collaboration mode.  Not being ready for millions users at time or having tech debt after the MVP stage - not condemnation. Let’s find the right way to handle this together!
  Our tech scaling department will work with your team back to back to find the most optimal solution for process, architecture, technology stack migration and development department restructure which suits best for your business.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>