<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on </title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 22:20:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stunning Presentations. Fast.</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/stunning-presentations-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 22:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/stunning-presentations-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-want-to-create-stunning-presentations-in-just-15-minutes&#34;&gt;Do you want to create stunning presentations in just 15 minutes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often when you need to make presentation it becomes entire saga of preparations, updates and fixes? All of it because you use wrong process and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive a bit into the process of creating a presentation. In most cases, you are on a call where 80% of the content is delivered verbally and only 20% is shown on the screen to highlight your thoughts. However, when preparing a presentation, you often spend 80% of your time creating only 20% of the content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Your Life [upd]</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/speed-up-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 08:41:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/speed-up-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of my friends and colleagues are asking where I’m rushing, why I want to get promotions as fast as possible. Being a director in your twenties, when you suppose to drink, do stupid stuff and spend time with friends. I work effectively more than 12 hours every day, on my pet projects, main job and other side quests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is one important thing you need to accept and understand. Our brain has been representing a lot of important data wrongly since the beginning due to established patterns, especially the ones that are much easier to recognize. I will provide you with a few examples that were eye-opening for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Security Quick Wins</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/data-security-quick-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:09:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/data-security-quick-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data security is a critical concern for any industry, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially important in digital company. With so much sensitive information being exchanged between different parties, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to have robust security measures in place to protect against malicious attacks and data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are some best practices and tips for ensuring data security in digital company? First and foremost, it&amp;rsquo;s important to implement strong access controls and encryption methods to protect data both in transit and at rest. This can include measures such as multi-factor authentication, VPNs, and SSL encryption. All our dev environments are hidden under VPN and password protected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity With Adhd</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/productivity-with-adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 17:19:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/productivity-with-adhd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JsT3KPYJFl4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started noticing that nowadays with enormous amount of distractions it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly hard to focus on things. And I was researching how people with ADHD actually staying hyper-focused, because fo them it must be even harder. Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder - ADHD can make it difficult to stay focused and productive, but there are strategies that I found useful and I will share them with you, which can help you stop procrastination and start getting things done even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have ADHD but facing lack of focus. Here are some tips on how to be productive with ADHD and how to trick your brain into staying on task:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Using AI Immediately</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/start-using-ai-immediately/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/start-using-ai-immediately/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-you-need-to-start-using-ai-as-soon-as-possible&#34;&gt;Why you need to start using AI as soon as possible&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey there, today we are talking why you need to start using AI now. Artificial Intelligence has been around for quite some time, and it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a concept of the future. Many businesses are already leveraging AI to improve their operations and stay ahead of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the need for AI implementation, the benefits of AI, and why you should not afraid of it. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notion Github Backup</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/notion-github-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 17:11:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/notion-github-backup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-is-expensive&#34;&gt;Data is expensive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write around 2-3 important notes a day. And don&amp;rsquo;t actually worry if my laptop will be stolen, but the data on it..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Im heavy notion user I was looking for automated backup solution. Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t trust notion, trust but verify, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;backup&#34;&gt;Backup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a private github repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/notion-github-backup/private_repo.webp&#34; alt=&#34;create private repo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to actions tab and click on &lt;code&gt;set up a workflow yourself -&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/notion-github-backup/setup_workflow.webp&#34; alt=&#34;set up workflow&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive blog post or Github Codespaces</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/recursive-blog-post-codespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 21:19:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/recursive-blog-post-codespaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I already posted a few thoughts about the iPad in the life of a developer. When I got a message from GitHub that I have beta access to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/features/codespaces&#34;&gt;codespaces&lt;/a&gt; I was super excited and started looking for a project which I can try to move to the cloud development environment to try it out. Due to the lack of small cozy projects which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t require docker-compose with 10 services, the first thing which I setup here is my blog since it&amp;rsquo;s just Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Env in Go V2</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/flexible-env-in-go-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 10:07:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/flexible-env-in-go-v2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lalabuy948genvutils&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lalabuy948/genvutils&#34;&gt;lalabuy948/genvutils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you probably saw my founding of two nice libraries that allow you beauty and easy abstraction on dot and just environment variables. You can check it &lt;a href=&#34;../../posts/flexible-env-in-go/&#34;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some time I decided to create another open-source library for the world and I merged the functionality of packages which you can find in the article above. I started from scratch and you are more than welcome to have look on it on my GitHub -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lalabuy948/genvutils&#34;&gt;github.com/lalabuy948/genvutils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashicorp Vault as Environment Manager</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/hashicorp-vault-as-environment-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 20:09:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/hashicorp-vault-as-environment-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-use-hashicorp-vault-as-dot-environment-manager&#34;&gt;How to use Hashicorp Vault as dot environment manager?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to share this because I was looking for small, simple and easy to use tool where I would store dotenv secrets for my apps. And I found this nice and elegant solution which will allow you to control your application secrets with small bash script. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-requirements&#34;&gt;Pre Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed vault&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish setup instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find nicely described steps here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.hashicorp.com/vault/getting-started/install&#34;&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
