<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>games on Mr. Popov</title>
    <link>/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in games on Mr. Popov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniil Popov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:59:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mini Space Journey</title>
      <link>/posts/mini-space-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:59:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mini-space-journey/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally released 🎉 Use for social media: #MiniSpaceJourney
&amp;ldquo;Mini Space Journey&amp;rdquo; is an innovative game for the Apple Watch that takes players on a thrilling adventure through outer space. Instead of using the watch&amp;rsquo;s accelerometer and gyroscope, the game utilizes the unique crown button on the side of the watch to navigate the player&amp;rsquo;s spacecraft. This makes for a unique and interactive gaming experience that is not found in other Apple Watch games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steamdeck for Whom?</title>
      <link>/posts/steamdeck-for-whom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 11:20:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/steamdeck-for-whom/</guid>
      <description>Look dear readers, I’m not even suppose to write such an articles, since I’m an inspiring manager and have to motivate people becoming better and so on. I not going to lie right, manager in IT department has nothing to do with people motivation or being a great example for productivity. I play games and fuck it, I like it.
I used to fly quite a lot and still do and I was constantly looking for on-the-go solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Must Play iOS Games</title>
      <link>/posts/must-play-ios-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/must-play-ios-games/</guid>
      <description>After I started working from home I got a bit more time to play games and would like to share my favorite ones. There are a few criteria by which I was compiling these lists. First of all, games should be optimized for the iPhone and iPad, games shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bugs or unstable performance. And of course, keep in mind that it&amp;rsquo;s my taste and I would love to discover new projects - drop your favorite in comments below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
