<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>people on Mr. Popov</title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in people on Mr. Popov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniil Popov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 08:41:40 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Your Life</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/speed-up-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 08:41:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/speed-up-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Most of my friends and colleagues are asking where I’m rushing, why I want to get promotions as fast as possible. Being a director in your twenties, when you suppose to drink, do stupid stuff and spend time with friends. I work effectively more than 12 hours every day, on my pet projects, main job and other side quests.
Here is one important thing you need to accept and understand. Our brain has been representing a lot of important data wrongly since the beginning due to established patterns, especially the ones that are much easier to recognize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity With Adhd</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/productivity-with-adhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 17:19:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/productivity-with-adhd/</guid>
      <description>I started noticing that nowadays with enormous amount of distractions it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly hard to focus on things. And I was researching how people with ADHD actually staying hyper-focused, because fo them it must be even harder. Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder - ADHD can make it difficult to stay focused and productive, but there are strategies that I found useful and I will share them with you, which can help you stop procrastination and start getting things done even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have ADHD but facing lack of focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Using AI Immediately</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/start-using-ai-immediately/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/start-using-ai-immediately/</guid>
      <description>Why you need to start using AI as soon as possible Hey there, today we are talking why you need to start using AI now. Artificial Intelligence has been around for quite some time, and it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a concept of the future. Many businesses are already leveraging AI to improve their operations and stay ahead of the competition.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the need for AI implementation, the benefits of AI, and why you should not afraid of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Expensive Gift</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/most-expensive-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 16:06:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/most-expensive-gift/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;This story happened to me yesterday. My sister and I have birthdays quite close to each other, with only a 6-day difference. Since I&amp;rsquo;m living abroad, we&amp;rsquo;ve celebrated together at our parents&amp;rsquo; place for the past couple of years. And since it&amp;rsquo;s their place, they sometimes invite their friends to such events as an extra occasion to reunite with them. This time, they invited one of their friends who is somewhat welcome, but we always hope she will cancel her invite, you know, being polite and all this stupid shit human bags are doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Travel Policy</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-travel-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:11:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-travel-policy/</guid>
      <description>General guidelines
✅ As the best practice we use the most affordable and efficient type of transportation and stays. The price of the stay and travel must be free or the provider has to pay our company for promoting them on tiktok. For those employees who didn’t reach 5 mln. subscribers and not able to get a bargain with the provider, the price of the stay and transportation must be covered by the employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Opportunity of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-opportunity-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/best-opportunity-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>✅ Motivating and adequate leader charging you with motivation for the whole day. You will grow as a professional and become stronger personality. We won’t use shocker on you for first week.
✅ Young team, this year we had just one fight. The oldest developer is 59, but he has a young soul and using electro scooter. Great atmosphere in the office where we blame everyone equally.
✅ Modern technical stack, php 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wfh Wtf</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/wfh-wtf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/wfh-wtf/</guid>
      <description>Wfh - wtf? Working from home is post fake-pandemic trend which seems to make life of corpos even harder than paying higher taxes than others and feeding others because they became bigger and more successful than others, this is normal behavior of our undeveloped society and non-discipline minds. But what happened with small to medium bizes founded by entrepreneurs, who are real people and humans? This camp was divided into two extremes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Became Digital Nomad CTO</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/how-i-became-digital-nomad-cto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/how-i-became-digital-nomad-cto/</guid>
      <description>Or how I moved with one backpack and half suitcase. Foreword This story has begun on 08.06 of 2021. The CEO of our company invited me to his office. We discussed my half year review and etc, and he put an offer in front of me. I went through, and I have to admit it was a nice package. But here is a small thing, I had to move to Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BasicBB</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/basicbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 19:40:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/basicbb/</guid>
      <description>Basic Building Blocks My blog and GitHub slightly empty in the past few months. I started spending less time on coding itself. I guess this happened to me naturally. I was a software engineer for the past five years and I was building amazing things in good teams and companies. I started to feel that I would like to help other people more than being focus on personal success.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I started spending much more of my spare time on our family project which is called basicbb - Basic Building Blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t go to IT or even go out</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/dont-go-to-it-or-even-go-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:58:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/dont-go-to-it-or-even-go-out/</guid>
      <description>During massive panic around the world I got stuck at home the same as a lot of other people probably. And a lot of my friends watching on me because not much changed in my life, I didn’t lose my job and I busy every day even due to massive panic which causes lockdown. So, they started asking me what should I do to become a developer like you and do millions per month?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad HR experience or How new repo was born</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/bad-hr-experience-or-how-new-repo-was-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:03:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/bad-hr-experience-or-how-new-repo-was-born/</guid>
      <description>Logektor ⚡️ Forewords This repo has some background, let me tell about it. Once, quite some time ago, I came to the company on the interview, for quite good and interesting position. We were talking about what they need and what I will need to do on this position. Meeting it self was good and I was so excited about that position.
But after few days I received tests assignment from them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
