<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elixir on </title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/elixir/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elixir on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:07:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/elixir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elixir Phoenix Optimisations iPhone Safari</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-phoenix-optimisations-iphone-safari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:07:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-phoenix-optimisations-iphone-safari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re running a Phoenix LiveView application and your iOS Safari users are experiencing frozen pages, slow reconnects, or 10+ second hangs after returning from sleep — this article is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a production Phoenix LiveView application. The app worked great on desktop, but iPhone users kept reporting the same thing: the page would freeze or hang for several seconds after switching back from another app or unlocking their phone. Sometimes the page would never recover at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir Liveview Socket Reconnect</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-liveview-socket-reconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:22:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-liveview-socket-reconnect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-phoenix-liveview-reconnection-bug-a-deep-dive&#34;&gt;The Phoenix LiveView Reconnection Bug: A Deep Dive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encountered a critical bug in a Phoenix LiveView settings page that controlled hardware via MQTT. When the WebSocket connection dropped and LiveView automatically reconnected, stale form values were being sent back to the hardware, overwriting the current hardware state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir LiveView Single Binary [UPD]</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-liveview-single-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:55:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/elixir-liveview-single-binary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had two repos of Elixir, seventy-five LiveView components, five sheets of high-powered Phoenix channels, a saltshaker half-full of SQLite databases, and a whole multicolored collection of Burrito deployables, Tauri binaries, WebView wrappers, hot-reloaders&amp;hellip; Also, a quart of WebSockets, a quart of GenServers, a case of Ecto queries, a pint of raw BEAM bytecode, and two dozen supervisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that really worried me was the WebView. There is nothing in the world more helpless and irresponsible and depraved than a developer in the depths of a cross-platform binge, and I knew we&amp;rsquo;d get into that rotten stuff pretty soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Livebook to Phoenix on Vps</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/connect-livebook-to-phoenix-on-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 14:19:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/connect-livebook-to-phoenix-on-vps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://livebook.dev&#34;&gt;Livebook&lt;/a&gt; is very powerful application which can be used in many different ways with your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.phoenixframework.org&#34;&gt;Phoneix&lt;/a&gt; project.
I have few apps running on my VPS and sometimes I would like to run some functions without creating interface for them from admin side, such as cache clean up. Perhaps run some analytical queries to the database and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single File Chat in Elixir Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/single-file-chat-in-elixir-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 23:46:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/single-file-chat-in-elixir-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-phonenixplayground&#34;&gt;Meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexdocs.pm/phoenix_playground/readme.html&#34;&gt;PhonenixPlayground&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this library on github suggestions and I always wanted to have something simple and quick to test out LiveView prototypes. What can be quicker than opening Livebook and trying something there? Folks behind &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexdocs.pm/phoenix_playground/readme.html&#34;&gt;PhonenixPlayground&lt;/a&gt; made both of my wishes come true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like jump straight into the code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://livebook.dev/run?url=https%3A%2F%2Fmrpopov.com%2Fposts%2Fsingle-file-chat-in-elixir-phoenix%2Fphoenix-dirty-chat.livemd&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://livebook.dev/badge/v1/pink.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Run in Livebook&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
