<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-Growth on </title>
    <link>https://mrpopov.com/tags/self-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-Growth on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 14:43:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrpopov.com/tags/self-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Things I Learned as Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/top-5-things-i-learned-as-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 14:43:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/top-5-things-i-learned-as-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2023, I opened my own LLC to run a fractional CTO/consulting business. After almost a year, I learned some important things that could be useful for people who would like to make a change in their career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-never-trust-anyone-unless-the-contract-is-signed-and-the-invoice-is-paid&#34;&gt;1. Never trust anyone unless the contract is signed and the invoice is paid.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the title says, a potential client might be eager to work with you, but when it comes to the actual contract and work, they might suddenly disappear without any signs of life, even people with whom you thought you had a nice relationship. Lower your expectations to zero or sometimes below zero. Once the contract is signed and the invoice is paid, you can have a small relief. (This happened to me 9 out of 10 times, maybe something is wrong with me)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Highest ROI Asset</title>
      <link>https://mrpopov.com/posts/the-highest-roi-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 13:14:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrpopov.com/posts/the-highest-roi-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might feel hard times are approaching, failure of Silicon Valley Bank is not the only sign of what’s happening in the world. Enormous &lt;a href=&#34;https://truflation.com/&#34;&gt;https://truflation.com&lt;/a&gt; with a lot of excluded spheres in calculations and constant lie on reported numbers. The main question is how to protect yourself from upcoming “tsunami”, as some enlightened people are saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stocks, crypto, commodities, real estate, different currencies - all of this might evaporate in matter of a blink. Stocks unpredictable, crypto even worse. Commodities and real estate might nationalised. Any currency might hit hyper inflation or even if going to find a stable pair, you still need to do operations through banks which can refuse giving you real value back instead of digits on your phone screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
